<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>ArchLan Linux Blog</title>
        <link>https://archlan.github.io/documentation/blog</link>
        <description>ArchLan Linux Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 22:17:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lightdm doesn't start on the live ISO]]></title>
            <link>https://archlan.github.io/documentation/blog/03-post-lightdm-iso</link>
            <guid>03-post-lightdm-iso</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 22:17:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When booting in the ArchLan live environment, it is possible that the lightdm display manager didn't start automatically. If it's your case, just run this command:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When booting in the ArchLan live environment, it is possible that the lightdm display manager didn&#x27;t start automatically. If it&#x27;s your case, just run this command:</p><pre><code class="language-bash"># The password for the liveuser is &quot;archlan&quot;
$ sudo systemctl start lightdm.service
</code></pre><blockquote><p>This issue will be fixed in the next releases.</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Start systemd services that weren't automatically enabled]]></title>
            <link>https://archlan.github.io/documentation/blog/02-post-systemd</link>
            <guid>02-post-systemd</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 22:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[During the ArchLan ISO building, the file runbeforesquashfs.sh executes operations in the last steps of the ISO building process.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the ArchLan ISO building, the file <code>run_before_squashfs.sh</code> executes operations in the last steps of the ISO building process.
Some of these operations might not succesfully work. If you encounter issues, follow the steps in this post to solve them.</p><pre><code class="language-bash">$ nmcli
Error: NetworkManager is not running.
</code></pre><p>Follow the steps in this post to fix it.</p><ol><li>In order to get the NetworkManager service unit to work</li></ol><pre><code class="language-bash">$ sudo systemctl start NetworkManager.service
</code></pre><p>You should now be able to use network connection on your machine.</p><p>:::note
In the case you are facing any other problems related to the ArchLan ISO, submit an issue at <a href="https://github.com/archlan/iso/issues/new">ArchLan:Issues</a>
:::</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fix an issue with ArchLan packages repository signing]]></title>
            <link>https://archlan.github.io/documentation/blog/01-post-packages</link>
            <guid>01-post-packages</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 21:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ArchLan Linux has it's own package repository added to the pacman configuration.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ArchLan Linux has it&#x27;s own package repository added to the pacman configuration.
If, at some point, you encounter this error while trying to update;</p><pre><code class="language-bash">error: archlan-packages: signature from &quot;Lanhild (ArchLan Linux PGP key, made by @Lanhild.) &lt;archlan@protonmail.com&gt;&quot; is unknown trust
error: failed to synchronize all databases (invalid or corrupted database (PGP signature))
</code></pre><p>Follow the steps in this post to fix it.</p><ol><li>The first step is to import the ArchLan Linux gpg key from the keyserver to your machine:</li></ol><pre><code class="language-bash">$ sudo pacman-key --recv-keys 5F765E0E531F5B53
</code></pre><ol start="2"><li>By precaution, verify the fingerprint of the key:</li></ol><pre><code class="language-bash">$ sudo pacman-key --finger 5F765E0E531F5B53
</code></pre><ol start="3"><li>The last step is to locally sign the key:</li></ol><pre><code class="language-bash">$ sudo pacman-key --lsign-key 5F765E0E531F5B53
</code></pre><p>:::note
Once all these steps have been accomplished, you should be able to successfully update and install packages from the ArchLan repository.
:::</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>